吉恩  你的信件
Hey, Gene.
谢了  吉米
Thanks, Jimmy.
-特瑞纳  -吉米你好
- Trina. - Hey, Jimmy.
你有个包裹  丹
Got a package, Dan.
今天怎么样
How's it going?
还好吗
What's up?
哈姆林麦吉尔联合律所
-你好啊  -好你个头
- Hey. - Hey, yourself.
吉米  我现在很烦  有话快说
Jimmy, I'm really slammed. Just tell me what you need.
这是什么
What is it?
我不敢打开
I can't open it.
写了什么
So, what does it say?
我必须请你注意
I must call to your attention
这项新通过的
the newly passed Environmental Impact
《环境影响与可持续发展保障法案》
and Sustainability Assurance Act,
如你所知  这条法案
a statute that, as you know, went into effect
没有任何溯及既往的条款就直接生效了
without any ex post facto provisions in place.
你有时间吗  查克
You got a second, Chuck?
没有  我现在有点
Not really. I'm-I'm kind of--
-一会儿就好  我保证  -好吧
- It'll just take two seconds. I promise. - All right.
这是什么
What's this?
你开玩笑吗
Is this a joke?
没有  这是真的
No. No joke.
你通过了律师资格考试
You, you passed the Bar?
是的  我通过了
Yeah. I did.
我想着如果金能考过  我应该也行
I-I thought if Kim could do it, maybe I can, too, you know?
所以我在一个社区大学修完了
So I got my last few credits for undergrad
本科的最后几个学分
from a community college.
不只是逃兵役的在那上课
I mean, they're not just for draft dodgers
上的课也不只有瑜伽
and yoga classes, all right?
后来我上了一所肯要我的法学院
Then I found a law school that would accept me.
虽然不是乔治城大学[最好的法学院之一]
You know, wasn't Georgetown or anything, but...
是美属萨摩亚大学
The university of American Samoa.
函授学校啊
Oh. Correspondence school.
我总不能辞职  对吧
Well, I wasn't gonna quit work, right?
就晚上  还有周末学习
Day-nights, weekends, you know?
他们现在把这叫做"远程学习"
They call it "Distance learning" nowadays.
但这是被承认的  加油  小地蟹
But they're accredited. Go, Land Crabs.
于是我就参加了函授学习
So, you know, I did that.
律师资格考试简直太难了
And the Bar exam's a mother.
至少对我来说很难
I mean, for me it was.
前两次考试我都挂了
I failed it the first two times,
但我觉得这就像失去你的童贞
but I guess it's like losing your virginity --
第三次总有好运
third time's the charm.
这肯定花了你很多年时间
How, this must have taken you years.
你却一直对我保密
And you kept it a secret all this time.
你为什么不来向我求助
Why? You didn't come to me for help?
查克  你可是我认识的最忙的人
Jesus, Chuck, you're the busiest guy I know.
你每天都在做很重要的事
I mean, you're doing important shit.
我不知道说什么好了
I don't know what to say.
你为我感到骄傲吗
Well, are you proud of me?
当然了
Yes!
-绝对的  -谢谢
- Absolutely. - Thanks.
查克  这对我意义重大
Chuck, that means a lot.
我在想  如果你觉得合适的话
I was hoping, you know, if you think it's appropriate,
一旦我把宣誓什么的弄完了
once I get sworn in and everything...
你能考虑雇我吗
consider hiring me?
雇你来干嘛
As what?
律师啊
Oh. A-a lawyer.
当然了  肯定的
Obviously. Yeah.
我要和霍华德还有其它的合伙人
Well, that's a question I'm gonna have to take up
商量一下这个问题
with Howard and the other partners.
这不是我一个人能做的决定
You know, it's not my decision alone.
但他们怎么会拒绝呢
But how could they say no?
你是如此干劲十足
So much drive.
吉米  看看你的成就
Jimmy, look what you've done here.
恭喜吉米
我跟他们说了要巧克力蛋糕
Oh, man. I told those guys devil's food.
我会替你告他们的
Yeah. Well, I will sue the store for you.
-很好  -苟富贵  勿相忘
- Good. - Just remember us when you're all big-time, huh?
我现在就忘记你了  巴特
I don't remember you now, Burt.
你代表的是我们收发室
You're representing mail room,
你这是告诉楼上那些混蛋...
so you show those upstairs jackholes how it gets--
大家伙在干什么呢  开派对吗
What are you folks up to? Having a party?
为这位新墨西哥州的新晋律师小小地庆祝一下
Just a little celebration on behalf of New Mexico's newest attorney.
我听说了  吉米  没看出来你还留了这手
I heard. Jesus, Jimmy, you're a regular Charlie Hustle.
-恭喜你  朋友  -谢谢
- Congratulations, my friend. - Oh, thank you. Thanks.
你要来块蛋糕吗
Would you like some cake?
-给你  -那我就不客气了
- Oh, here. - Uh, don't mind if I do.
你真的让我刮目相看  吉米
Really, really impressive, Jimmy.
我们都为你感到骄傲
We're all proud of you.
很抱歉打扰你们
Hey, I hate to interrupt.
我能和吉米单独说几句吗
But could you guys give Jimmy and me a moment?
-当然了  -没问题
- Sure. - Yeah, absolutely.
请坐吧
Please, sit down.
六个月之后再评估吧
Let's reassess in six months.
谢谢理解  吉米
Thanks for understanding, Jimmy.
你想让我把门关了还是留着
You want the door open or closed?
关上吧
Closed.
新墨西哥大学
法学院
你怎么样了
How's it going?
重新布置
Settling back in.
那就好
Great.
显然他们已经准备好见我们了
So, apparently, they are ready for us.
谢了  但是我午饭前想先处理点事
Oh, thanks, but I want to get a couple things done before lunch,
而且我还在整理...
and I'm still trying to settle --
来吧  金  这是你应得的
Come on, Kim. You deserve this.
来尽享此刻的荣誉吧
Come bask in the glow.
谢谢你们的到来
Thank you all for coming.
谢谢大家能在百忙之中抽出时间来
I appreciate you making time in the middle of your busy days.
我很高兴地宣布
I'm pleased to announce that
在与伯纳利欧县地检办公室
working closely with the Bernalillo County
共同合作之下
district attorney's office,
霍华德·哈姆林
克雷格·凯特尔曼律师
我们对前财务主管克雷格·凯特尔曼的
we have reached plea agreement
认罪协议达成了一致
for former treasurer Craig Kettleman.
我们相信这是一个公平公正的结果
We believe this is a just and fair outcome
结案后  凯特尔曼先生也表示深深后悔
and brings to a close an incident Mr. Kettleman deeply regrets.
他将尽力弥补他的过错...
He is committed to making amends for his mistakes...
有什么需要帮助的吗
Can I help you?
我是来找兰德里太太的
Yeah, I'm here to see Mrs. Landry.
请在这里签名
Sign in right here, please.
你是她的亲属吗
Are you a relative?
律师
Lawyer.
但我的客户就像我的家人
But I treat my clients like family.
矶鹞渡生活协助中心
你知道她在哪吗
Y-you know where to find her?
知道  谢了
Yeah. Thanks.
早上好  伙计们
Good morning, folks. Hi.
我是吉米·麦吉尔
Jimmy McGill. I...
挑张名片吧  随便挑
Hey, pick a card, any card.
好  最近怎么样
All right. How's it going there?
很好  手劲还挺...
Good. Whoa! Not so t--
名片仙子给他的意外惊喜
Little surprise from the card fairy.
背部收紧
Give me back squeeze.
把水下我看不到的都紧绷起来
Squeeze whatever you got that's below the water that I can't see.
兰德里太太  只要再签几个名
All right, Mrs. Landry, just a few more signatures,
然后就没问题了
and, uh that will be done.
再来一块饼干吧
Would you like another hydrox?
不了  谢谢  我快吃撑了
No, thank you. I'm all hydrox'd out.
想吃的话就自己拿吧
Well, please help yourself if you change your mind.
好了  那里
All right. That one.
好了  还有这里
Okay. And that one.
然后就好了
And that is it.
遗嘱
真是长舒一口气
What a relief.
好几年前就该弄好的
I should have done this years ago.
这种事大家都喜欢拖
Well, people do tend to put it off.
但每个人都该早点立下遗嘱
But everybody should have a will.
要告诉你的老年朋友哦
Please tell your friends.
一共是一百四十元
And that comes to $140.
现金和支票都可以
And I'm happy to take, uh, cash or a check
或者说  还是现金吧
or, uh...cash.
稍等一会
O-one moment.
你能给我写一张支票吗
Could you write me a check?
时间太久了
Well, it's been so long,
我...我不知道我户头上的钱够不够
I -- I-I really don't know if I have enough in my account.
实在很抱歉
I am so sorry.
实在是太糟糕了  但是...
Thi-- this is awful, but...
我只有四十三元
all I have is $43.
好吧
Okay.
我可以去找他们预支一点
Now, I could ask for an advance.
我真的很抱歉
I-I-I am so sorry.
没关系
It's fine.
我都不知道该说什么了  太糟糕了
I-I don't know what to say. This is awful.
遗嘱你可以先拿着  等我拿到津贴
You could keep the will until I get my allowance,
应该下礼拜就能拿到
and -- and that should only be until the end of next week.
没有那个必要  这是我的地址
Okay, that's not necessary. Here's my address.
你有钱了就寄给我  行吗
Just mail it to me when you've got it, all right?
我还是  还是收一百二吧
And why don't we, uh -- we'll just make it an even $120.
行吧
All right?
谢谢
Thank you.
生活愉快
You have a nice day.
不好意思  "津贴"
Excuse me. Allowance?
你家人还给你钱吗
Your family has you on an allowance?
不不不  是我的钱
Oh, no, no. It's -- it's my money.
由矶鹞渡发给我
I just get it from Sandpiper Crossing.
五百块一个月
$500 a month --
我不懂
I don't understand.
你应该有社保支票
You should have social security checks...
再加上我们之前说的养老金
plus that pension we talked about.
你怎么还需要津贴
So how are you on an allowance?
那些支票都寄给矶鹞渡
Well, the checks go to Sandpiper,
然后他们抽掉我的费用和开销
and then they take out my fees and -- and my expenses.
你还是进来吧
Why don't you just come on in?
我怕我解释得不够到位
I'm afraid I'm not explaining it very well.
我这里有个声明  在哪来着
I -- I have statements here...somewhere.
在哪  这里
Somewhere. Okay. Here...
所以你的养老金和社保
So your pension and social security
都是直接寄给矶鹞渡的人吗
goes straight to the Sandpiper people?
他们拿走他们需要的钱
They take out -- they take out what they need,
然后再给我发津贴
and then -- and then I get my allowance.
剩下的钱都打到我的储蓄账户里
And -- and all the rest goes into my savings account.
没什么猫腻
It's really all very above-board.
很多地方都这样子
A lot of places do it this way.
他们对这里每个人都这样吗
This is how they do it for everybody around here?
没错  他们这是在帮我们省事
Well, yes, they -- they try to make everything easy for us.
兰德里太太  你朋友在吗
Mrs. Landry, are any of your friends around
我想跟他们谈谈
who I could talk to?
我看到你花了...不知道你有没有注意到
I see you spent -- now, I don't know if you noticed --
187.5元花在4-10-12这条上
$187.50 on 4-10-12.
你知道4-10-12是什么吗
Do you know at 4-10-12 is?
不  想知道的话  你必须看背面
No. In order to find out, you have to look on the back.
好吗  看这个
Okay? And see this key.
我看到你戴了老花镜  能借我用一下吗
I see you have reading glasses. Can I borrow your glasses?
-可以  -谢谢你
- Yes. - Thank you.
这个可以帮到我
Oh, these are gonna help me,
但我不知道能不能看清楚
but I don't know if they'll do the trick.
字太小了
So tiny.
4-10-12...
我想可能是棉签  我也说不准
I think it might be q-tips. I can't tell.
可能是个意外  不过我们该调查一下
It's probably an accident, but we should look into it.
你们认为呢
Don't you think?
他们不是故意这样做的
They're not doing this intentionally.
可能哪里出了错
Okay? This could be a mistake.
不过如果我们纠正这个错误
But if we correct the mistake,
你们就会拿回一些钱  那就公平了
then you'll get some money back, and it'll be fair.
查克
Hey, Chuck.
我的那些盒子  上次留在这的...
My boxes, the ones I left...
矶鹞渡...
Sandpiper Crossing...
你做了我那些遗嘱吗
Did you do my wills?
是的  我做了
Yes, I did.
你能看看那个吗
Hey. Would you look at that?
-谢谢  -别谢我
- Thank you. - Don't thank me.
这事只有一次
This was a one-time thing,
别以为我看不出你想干什么
and don't think I don't see what you were doing here.
你想演《汤姆历险记》  想让我为你刷栅栏
You wanted to play Tom Sawyer, wanted me to paint the fence,
老天呐  我居然上钩了
and god help me, it worked.
你需要帮忙吗
You need help?
去雇一个助手  靠自己解决问题
Hire a para-legal, stand on your own two feet.
好的  我会的
Yeah. Sure. I'll do that.
你根本没在听我说话
You're not even listening to me.
不  我听见了  查克  行了吗
No, I -- I hear you, Chuck, okay?
自力更生  这样很好  你能看一下这个吗
Self-reliance. It's great stuff. Would you look at this?
不是说了你自己解决吗
What did I just say?
就看一眼  好吗  就这里
Ta-take a look, okay? Just right here.
你看到了吗
Do you see what I see?
我只要求你看一眼  求你了
All I'm asking is for you to take a look. Please?
"矶鹞渡..."
"Sandpiper Crossing..."
那是一间养老院  生活协助中心
It's a retirement home, assisted living.
这是他们寄给居住者的一张月结账单
It's -- this is one of their monthly invoices they send their residents.
我到底要找什么
What exactly am I looking for?
不需要什么惊天动地的东西
It's nohing earth-shaking.
只是一些小地方  类似...
Just little things, little things like --
类似这个
like this right here.
十四块付给118-62条
$14 for code 118-62.
118-62是什么
What's 118-62?
我也想知道
I wonder.
这怎么看得清  简直就是缩微胶卷啊
How could you even read this? It's like microfilm.
118-62是面巾纸
118-62 is facial tissue.
十四块钱买一盒纸巾
14 bucks for a box of Kleenex.
是的  我还找到了别的
Yeah, I found others.
三块五一卷厕纸
There's $3.50 for a single roll of toilet paper,
二十二块钱一瓶阿司匹林
22 bucks for a bottle of aspirin.
这很明显是过高收费
It's a clear pattern of overcharging.
单项数额不高  但是加起来钱就很多
Nothing huge, but it adds up to real money.
你看这个
I mean, here, look.
这个女人  上个月被敲了四百块钱
This woman -- she got soaked for like 400 bucks last month.
而且他们很明显
And there's a pretty solid attempt
想要掩盖事实真相
at concealment of that fact,
在我看来  这应该构成...
which to my way of thinking, makes it...
诈骗罪  这是我经手的吗
Fraud. This was in work I did?
是的  你一定是漏掉了
Yeah, you must have missed it.
查克  我运气很好  不是吗
Um, look, Chuck, I got lucky, right?
真的是时来运转了
Even a stopped clock is right twice a day.
这可不是小规模企业  对吗
And this is no mom-and-pop outfit, okay?
我调查了一下
I dug around a little.
养老院是一家房地产投资信托公司所有
They're owned by some kind of real-estate investment trust.
还需要搜集更多资料  但很可能是个大案子
I'm working at getting more info, but this could be big.
这是个大案子  不是吗
I mean, this could be a big case, right?
如果不光是这些账单
Well...if it's more than a few errant billings
如果这是有组织的  而且你找到了运作模式
and if it's systematic and you establish a pattern,
可以提出集体诉讼
it could be class-action.
我该做什么  下一步该怎么办
What do I do now? I mean, what next?
你需要搜集更多的资料
Well, you're gonna need more information.
你也不想草率行事吧
You don't want to go off half-cocked.
我会做十足的准备
Full cock. Okay.
不  我要回去一趟
No, I -- I'm gonna head back there.
谢谢你  你是最棒的
Thank you. You're the best.
矶鹞渡
回来见兰德里夫人
Back to see Mrs. Landry.
好吧  什么情况
Okay. What gives?
抱歉  先生  新政策
Sorry, sir. New policy.
我们担心会有教唆[引诱]行为发生
We're concerned about solicitation on premises.
我不是小白脸  如果你在暗示这个的话
I'm not a gigolo, if that's what you're implying.
法律教唆
Legal solicitation.
我们有义务保护居住者不受骚扰
We're obligated to protect our residents from being harassed,
我们也有权利拒绝你进入
and we have the right to refuse entry.
这里有我的客户
I have clients in there.
现在他们有见我的合法权利
Now, they have the legal right to meet with me.
那你必须和他们安排在别处见面
Well, you'll just have to arrange to meet them elsewhere.
拜托  老兄  来真的吗
Oh, come on, guys. Seriously?
你们在这上演《超世纪谍杀案》吗
What, are you making Soylent Green back there?
好吧  好吧
It's -- all right, okay.
我走  行了吧
I-I'm backing away. Yeah?
你知道吗  这...
You know what? Uh...this --
他们俩把我推得肚子疼
Hey, this has gotten me a little bit stirred up down there.
用一下卫生间可以吗
Can I use your restroom?
求你了  我有肠易激综合征
Please, it's -- I've got I.B.S.
去吧
Go ahead.
"致矶鹞渡生活协助中心
"To Sandpiper Crossing...
詹姆斯·摩根·麦吉尔律师的委托人
"...clients of James M. McGill...
现通知贵中心"
This is to inform you to stay..."
先生  你还好吧
Sir? Are you all right in there?
"我们认为...有违约行为"
"We believe that... breach of contract..."
先生  快出来  我够耐心的了
Come on, now, sir. I've been very patient.
"有明显的违法行为
"...clear pattern of malfeasance...
严重伤害了委托人的感情"
This is a negligent infliction of emotional distress."
先生  你上完了就赶快给我出来
Sir, I really need you to finish up and come out now.
"请在本周末前与我联系
"...contact by the end of the week
否则我将不得不采取必要措施"
"or I will be forced to move forward."
先生  你快给我出...
Sir, I need you to finish up --
这是律师函  现告知贵中心
This is a demand letter informing Sandpiper Crossing
你们涉嫌有组织诈骗我方委托人
of pending litigation for defrauding
收取过高费用  将遭到起诉
my clients through systematic overcharging.
你们在粉碎文件  以为我是聋子吗
You're shredding in there! I'm not deaf!
我都听见了  快给我停下
I can hear you! Stop right now!
这封律师函意味着正式进入法律程序
This here -- this makes it official, right?
如果你们再不停下来
If you don't stop shredding right now,
你们就是在破坏证据  用法律术语说
that's destruction of evidence -- spoliation!
就是销毁罪证  那可是重罪
That's what it's called, and it's a felony!
现在就给你的律师打电话  说是我说的
So call your lawyers right now and tell them I said that --
堂堂詹姆斯·麦吉尔先生
me -- James McGill esquire!
我告诉你们  你们会后悔的
I'm telling you guys, big mistake! Aah!
你现在不方便接电话吗
Am I calling at a bad time?
没  没有
No, not at all.
最近怎么样
How you doing?
不错  还过得去
Uh, pretty good. Getting by.
你呢
How about you?
凑合
Getting by.
听到你的声音我真高兴
It's good to hear from you.
是啊  我最近...最近事情很多
Yeah. I-I've been -- There's been a lot going on.
你知道的
You know how it is.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
是这样
Uh, listen.
我想让你帮我个忙
I was -- was hoping maybe you could do me a favor.
你能照顾一下凯莉吗
Do you think you could watch Kaylee?
只收现金
后天我去值班的时候看着她就行
It'd be during my shift the day after tomorrow.
我也不想麻烦你  但保姆这次...
Look, I hate to ask, but my regular sitter's down --
你有任何需要尽管开口
Anything you need, I'll be there.
你那时能下班吗  不要影响你工作
You can get off work? I don't want to impose or anything.
没关系  什么时候都行
No. Anytime.
一点也不影响
It's not an imposition.
谢谢  太感谢了
Thanks. Appreciate it.
别客气
Yeah, no problem.
那就一点四十五分吧
At a quarter to 2:00?
好的
I'll see you then.
好
Okay.
真臭
Jesus!
快出来
Come on.
在哪呢
Where is it?
真他妈恶心
God damn it!
就是那样也没搞定
And it didn't even make it fit.
然后我就说  "我们还没有做完呢
And I'm like, "It's not like we're close to being done.
你就不能另找个人来做吗"
I mean, can't you get somebody else to do it?"
说的对
Right.
他们给的钱也太少了
They don't pay any of us enough for this shit.
然后我们就争论了很久
You know what? And it's going on and on and on.
我就说
And so I'm like,
"明明是你们的问题  怎么怪到我头上"
"Why are you making your problems my problems?"
就是  好像你的麻烦还不够多似的
Right. Like you don't have enough problems of your own.
没错  我就是这么说的
Exactly! That's exactly what I'm saying.
谢谢  但是他...
Thank you. But he just...
詹姆斯·麦吉尔
James McGill.
麦吉尔先生
Mr. McGill,
我是斯韦卡特和考科利公司的里奇·斯韦卡特
Rich Schweikart of Schweikart and Cokely.
我们是代理
We're the law firm
矶鹞渡生活协助中心的律所
representing Sandpiper Crossing Assisted Living.
您今晚过得怎么样
How are you this evening?
还不错  谢谢  你呢
Quite well, thank you. How are you?
我也不错
Doing fine. Doing fine.
很抱歉这么晚打电话  您现在方便说话吗
I'm sorry to call so late. Did I catch you at a bad time?
没关系  你说吧
No, no. No, it's fine.
可你为什么声音这么小
It's just that you're whispering.
我在看歌剧呢
I'm at the opera.
什么歌剧啊
Oh. What opera?
《魔笛》
Magic Flute.
莫扎特的啊  不错
Mozart! Lovely.
那我长话短说吧
Well, I'll try not to keep you.
今天我们收到了您的...一样东西
We received...something from you today,
我们不清楚这到底是什么
And we're not quite sure what.
是律师函
It's a demand letter.
但令我们迷惑不解的是  它怎么写在...
Well, it was a little confusing 'cause it was written on, uh...
我得以最快速度写完
Well, I had to write it quickly
因为你的委托人正试图销毁罪证
because your clients were in the process of destroying evidence.
麦吉尔先生  您是指用碎纸机粉碎文件吧
Mr. McGill, if you're talking about shredding documents,
那既不反常  也不违法
That's neither irregular nor illegal.
美国所有的公司都会碎纸
Every business in America does it.
你说的是碎纸  我说的是销毁罪证
You say potato, I say spoliation.
您还是给我解释下  什么销毁罪证
Maybe you should walk me through what you're alleging here.
律师函里已经写得很清楚了
I believe it's all in the letter.
我没说里面没有
Uh, uh, I-I'm not saying it's not,
但有点儿难读懂
but it's a bit hard to read.
下次我会用双层纸
Next time, I'd use double-ply.
咱们别太关注纸质  好吗
Let's not fixate on the medium, okay?
我们来讨论一下内容
Let's look at the message.
现在  你的委托人面临着虐待老人
Now, your clients are facing multiple counts of elder abuse
诈骗  不公平交易等多项指控
and -- and fraud and deceptive and unfair trade practices,
这还只是开始  知道吗
and that's just the start, okay?
我不是个爱打赌的人
I'm not a betting man,
但我打赌我会找到更多证据
but I bet the farm I'll find more.
麦吉尔先生  你跟查尔斯·麦吉尔是亲戚吗
Mr. McGill, are you related to Charles McGill?
他是我哥哥
He's my brother.
是吗  他最近怎么样
Yeah? How's he doing these days?
我不知道这有什么关系
I - I fail to see the relevance of this.
坦白讲  我打这通电话的唯一原因就是
Frankly, the only reason that I made this phone call
出于对查尔斯的尊重
was out of respect for Charles
而你可能跟他是亲戚关系
on the off chance that you might be related to him.
我的搭档建议最好的回应就是
My partner suggested that the best response
地方法院可以惩处提起非正当诉讼的律师
根据第十一条法规对你进行惩处
would be to send a Rule 11 letter and have you sanctioned,
但我不想直接走那一步
but I didn't want to jump to that immediate length.
这样吧  你别吓唬我了
Hey, how about you stop trying to rattle my cage
请正面做出回应
and just, you know, respond to the merits?
这就是我的回应  麦吉尔先生
This is my response, Mr. McGill...
你威胁说要提起诉讼并非出于善意
You have no good-faith basis to threaten any litigation.
这是勒索  你我心知肚明
This is a shakedown, and we both know it.
如果你非要得寸进尺  我也没办法了
Now, if you push this any further, my hands will be tied.
抱歉在晚上打扰你
Sorry for interrupting your evening.
享受《魔笛》吧
Enjoy "The Magic Flute."
来吹我的魔力"长笛"吧
Blow my magic flute.
该死
Son of a bitch!
吉米  你在干什么
Jimmy, what are you doing here?
查克
Oh, uh, Chuck, um...
很抱歉我这个样子
Sorry to... show up like this.
我只是需要一个地方工作
I just needed space to work.
这都是什么
What is all this?
你在我的餐厅干什么
What have you done to my dining room?
他们在销毁证据  矶鹞渡那些人
They were spoliating -- the Sandpiper people.
他们不让我进去
They wouldn't let me in,
我能看到他们在粉碎文件
and I could see that they were shredding.
我写了律师函  并交给了他们
I wrote them a demand letter, and I gave it to them.
-你闯进了养老院吗  -是生活协助中心
- You broke in to a nursing home? - Assisted living.
你偷了他们的垃圾
And you stole their garbage.
-天哪  -不  垃圾桶在公共区域
- My god. - No, it was in public.
没有上锁  什么都没有
There was no lock, no nothing.
我把盖子打开  就在里面了
I just lifted the lid, and there it was.
这种情况下又没什么隐私可言
There's no reasonable expectation of privacy
难道不是吗
in that situation, is there?
如果流浪汉可以睡里面
You can't say it's private
那就不能称之为隐私
if a hobo can use it as a wigwam.
这是标准  不是吗
That's -- that's the standard, right?
如果动物或者流浪者可以进入的话
If animals or vagrants can get in?
差不多是这样的
More or less, yes.
所以这些都是合法的
Okay, so this is all legal.
完完全全合法的
I mean, it's completely above-the-belt legal.
我只需要弄清楚他们在试图掩盖什么
I just need to figure out what they're trying to cover up.
一般人不这么粉碎文件
You know, you don't shred like this
除非要隐瞒什么事  对吗
unless you got something to hide, am I right?
-也不一定  -得了吧  查克
- Not necessarily. - Oh, come on, chuck.
我这个律师出现
A lawyer shows up,
开始调查他们的小阴谋  之后就粉碎文件
starts figuring out their little scheme, and suddenly this?
这绝不是巧合  这里面一定有鬼
No, it's not a coincidence. It's in here.
至少不是横切的
Well, at least it's not crosscut.
横切的纸张更细碎  更难阅读
我不会影响你的
Look, you won't even know I'm here, okay?
我只需要一个安静的地方
I just need some space and some quiet,
而且我弄完了就走
and I'll be out of your hair as soon as I --
停下停下  没关系的  你可以在这儿工作
Stop, stop. It's okay. You can work here.
谢谢
Thanks.
我不介意有人陪伴
I don't mind the company.
你需要一杯咖啡
You look like you could use a cup of coffee.
天哪  当然
Good god, yes.
我去煮咖啡
I'll put it on.
抬起来
Up, up. Up.
上帝啊
God's sweet sake.
太好了  你醒了
Oh, good. You're up.
天哪  查克  我睡了多久
Well, jesus, Chuck, how long have I been asleep?
查克  你怎么
Chuck, how did you...?
真不敢相信
I -- I can't believe this. Uh...
谢谢你  你真帮了大忙
Uh, thank you. This is a huge help.
我感觉就像是在暴风雪中铲雪
I felt like I was shoveling snow in a blizzard.
越来越明了了
Well, it gets better.
这是什么
What's this?
这就是确凿证据
It's your smoking gun.
这是  注射器的发票
It's a, uh... invoice for syringes.
没错  从哪里来的
Yes. From?
莫里西医疗用品  内布拉斯加州林肯市
Morrissey Medical Supply -- Lincoln, Nebraska.
-所以呢  -相信我
- So? - Trust me.
现在我们需要查看判例法
Meanwhile, we need to start pulling case law --
1961到1968年间
any precedent dealing with 18 U.S.C.
任何跟美国法典第18章相关的
1961 to '68.
也许查看1978年修订的《新墨西哥州法令》
Probably not a bad idea to pull 30.47.1
第30章第47节第1款也是个不错的主意
from NMSA...uh, 1978.
我其实觉得那没什么用
I don't think that's gonna play, really,
但对我们来说是个不错的开始
but it's a good opening salvo for us.
等一下  "我们"
Wait, "us"?
我们要一起处理这个案子吗
We're working together on this?
你来决定啊  吉米
Mm. That's up to you, Jimmy.
因为
'Cause --
好了
All right.
好了好了  开始工作吧
All right. All right. Let's get to work.
-我是金·韦克斯勒  -美女  你好啊
- Kim Wexler. - Hey, gorgeous.
一上来就甜言蜜语
Oh, man. Sweet-talking right out of the gate?
你想要什么  快说
You want something. Make it fast.
-我急着回家  -好
- I want to go home. - Okay, okay.
你能帮我在万律数据库里查个东西吗
Will you look something up for me on Westlaw?
求你了
Please?
还好我比较好说话
You're lucky I'm a pushover.
好了  说吧
All right. Hit me.
谢谢
Thank you.
塞迪玛控告因克士公司一案
Uh, anything on Sedima v. Imrex,
均为促成《反诈骗和腐败组织法案》的经典案例
施莱辛格控告迪士尼一案
Slesinger v. Disney,
霍姆斯控告证券投资者保护公司一案
Holmes v. S.I.P.C. --
别急  慢点  迪士尼
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Slow down, slow down. v. Disney.
还有霍姆斯控告证券投资者...
Holmes v. S.I.--
-保护公司  -对
- D.C.- Yeah.
还有1978年修订的《新墨西哥州法令》
And, uh, anything on 57.12.1-24
57章12节1到24款
NMSA, 1978.
好吧
Uh, okay.
你最好给我划个范围吧
It would help if I knew what you were looking for here.
没范围  我要所有信息
Anything, everything.
什么  你是让我光给你念摘要么
What? You want me to just read you the head notes or something?
不是  全打印出来  整个案子
No, no, print it -- full cases,
还有其他引用过这些案子的案例
and any cases that cite to those cases.
每一个援引过的案子都不放过
Shepardize like the wolf's at the door.
天呐  吉米  这得有好几千页呢
Jesus, Jimmy, that's gonna be thousands of pages.
求求你了
Pretty please with sugar on top?
你还欠我个人情呢
Come on. You owe me one.
没错  但这得忙好几个小时呢
Yes, I do, but this is gonna take hours.
-还有  谁出钱  -霍华德
- And who do I bill it to? - Bill it to Howard.
他的工号是
I still remember his code --
1933  刚好是希特勒掌权那年
1933, same year Hitler came to power.
呵呵  我才不能把账记我老板头上
You're not funny. I'm not billing it to my boss.
那记你头上吧  我回头还你
How about yours? I'll pay you back.
吉米  这可得三四百块呢
Jimmy, this is 300, 400 bucks worth of printing.
让会计发现了  我就别想干了
The accountants will find it and I'll get fired,
此路不通
which sounds fun and all, but no.
好吧  稍等
Okay. Hold on a sec.
金没有工号不能打印
Uh, Kim can't print without a code.
我能不能过去做些笔记  然后再回来
Should I go over there, take notes, and come back?
算了  那得抄到什么时候
No, no, no. It would take too long.
用我的吧  1868
Use mine -- 1868.
好吧
Yeah.
用1868  查克的工号
1868. Use that. It's Chuck's.
你要用查克的工号啊
You're using Chuck's number?
他本人知道吗
Does Chuck know you're using Chuck's number?
我们在一起研究个案子
We're working on something together.
记得打印好送他家去
And bring it over to his place after.
-非常感谢  -稍等  别挂
- You're a lifesaver. - Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait!
你俩一起研究案子吗
You're working a case together?
对  你别声张  这可是个大案子...
Yeah. Keep this under your hat, but it's gonna be huge --
很可能成为集体诉讼
maybe a class-action, even.
能弄到一百万甚至两百万呢
We think it'll settle for $1 million, maybe $2 million.
你俩咋合作呢
How does that work?
查克是哈姆林麦吉尔联合律所的合伙人
Chuck's a partner at HHM.
咋了
So what?
我对查克的合伙协议一清二楚
Look, I know Chuck's partnership agreement chapter and verse.
他可以和外人合作
He can work with outside parties.
那条约只适用于小案子
That clause is intended for small-time stuff,
无偿的案子
pro bono cases.
那又怎样  我就是为了公益
So? I'm bono. I'm very bono.
查克很牛逼的  他们不敢造次
Chuck's a rock star, okay? They'll work it out.
查克能行吗  上次我见他时  他...
And Chuck can handle this? Last time I saw him, he was --
上次他失控了  好吗
Last time you saw him, he wasn't himself, okay?
现在他能行
This is good for him.
你说好就好
Okay.
又咋了
What?
我也说不清  只是...
I don't know. I'm just...
算了  我们待会儿见
Whatever. I'll see you in a couple hours.
好  我们叫披萨了
Okay. We're ordering a pizza, okay?
给你留一块
I'll save you a slice.
你要是再把不同颜色混在一起
Now, you know, if you don't separate those,
最后就全成棕色的了
You're gonna end up with brown.
都在家吗
Hello?
在里面
We're in here.
我们在做泥塑呢
We're playing sculptor.
她就是米开朗琪罗再世  工作顺利吗
She's Michelangelina. How's work?
文艺复兴著名雕刻家
没啥特别的  你俩今天咋样
Eh, you know -- work. How did it go?
她特别好  很乖
Kid's a dream. She's easy.
以后也要乖乖的哦
And you better stay that way.
玩得开心吗  宝贝
How you doing, sweetie? Huh?
我该走了
Well, I better be going.
别急  过会儿再走吧
Oh, wait. Hang on a sec, would you?
我有事想跟你聊聊
I want to talk to you about something.
怎么了
What's up?
这钱咋办啊
I want to know what I should do with this.
好几个星期了
I've been carrying it around for weeks,
我天天都随身带着
like holding on to it.
不管放哪儿  我都放心不下
Every place I put it feels wrong.
我原本想放到教堂奉献盘里  但...
I thought about putting it in the collection plate, but...
这样有点...  我也说不清
it seemed -- I don't know.
马蒂去世后  日子挺拮据
Look, with Matty gone, I have expenses,
靠他的抚恤金我们勉强度日  但...
and the death benefit helped, but...
我想问你的是
what I want to ask you is...
这钱能花吗
...can I spend this?
史黛西  如果这笔钱
Stace, if this money helps you and Kaylee,
能够帮助你和凯莉的话
if it does a single good thing in this world,
你想怎么花就怎么花
then you spend every penny.
这下我放心了
That's a relief. It'll help a lot.
当然这只是杯水车薪
Of course, it's only a drop in the bucket.
我发誓  我知道的每个人都觉得不好用
I swear, everyone I know has had problems with them.
我就有一辆  控制引擎的电脑
I had one. The computer in the engine --
在经过落基山脉时锁死了
It locked in the middle of the Rockies.
对呀  它说引擎过热了什么的
Yeah, it decided I was overheating, and that was it.
一百英里都没有维修的地方
Yeah. I couldn't get it fixed for a hundred miles.
我只好把它拖到特鲁莱德去了
I had to have it towed to Telluride.
真是受够了
It was unbelievable.
不  是电脑芯片  是那个小...
No, it's -- it's the chip. It's the little...
对啊  花了八百多块  还不算...
Yeah, it's like 800 bucks, not counting...
人力
labor.
莫里西医疗用品
小梅  我一会儿再打给你
Hey, Mel, can I call you back?
查克  矶鹞渡的人来啦
Chuck, the Sandpiper has landed.
先生们  我是吉米·麦吉尔
Gentlemen, I'm Jimmy McGill.
-欢迎  -里奇·斯韦卡特
- Welcome. - Rich Schweikart.
这是阿尔文·里斯  菲尔·杰尔根思
This is Alvin Reese. Phil jergens.
感谢光临
Thanks for coming.
我要请你们
Oh, whoa. I have to ask you.
把所有的电子设备留在车里
Uh, please leave electronics in the car --
笔记本电脑  手机  掌上电脑  手表
laptops, blackberries, palm pilots, watches.
凡是一碰就出声的都请留在车里
If you lick it and it goes bzzt, leave it here.
为什么
Why?
我哥哥查克有点过敏
My brother Chuck has a certain sensitivity.
是一种身体疾病
It's a medical condition.
这是来造访的代价
This is the price of admission.
我已经听说过了
Yeah, I heard about this.
放吧  没事儿的
Go ahead. It's fine.
好了
Here you go.
先生们  请随便坐
Make yourselves comfortable, gentlemen.
我马上就回来
I'll be right back.
好的
All right.
查克  来吧  哥
Chuck. Come on, buddy.
我...
I...
我不知道自己还行不行
I don't -- I don't know if I can do this.
你当然行的  好吧
You -- oh, you can do this, all right?
这些人...
These guys...
那些人啥也不是  好吧
Those guys -- they're nothing. Okay?
他们是活塞队你就是公牛队
They're the Pistons, and you're the Bulls.
好啦
All right?
你要做的就是一脸严肃地坐在那儿
All you got to do is sit there and look intimidating.
他们已经很怕你了  他们应该被吓到
They're scared of you already, and they should be.
你可是查尔斯·麦吉尔啊
You're Charles McGill.
我们走吧  去打败他们
Let's go. Let's go get 'em.
您还记得我吗  查尔斯
Do you remember me, Charles?
我们做过联合辩护啊
We were on a co-defence --
教会甜甜圈诉阿蒙多拉
Church's Donuts v. Amendola?
天啊  快十年前的事儿了吧
It was -- jesus -- 9, 10 years ago.
对啊
Yeah.
我们的客户起诉那些人
Oh, our guys were suing the other guys,
那些人又反过来起诉我们
and they were suing us right back,
再加上市政厅对我们都有不满
and the city had some grievance with everyone,
我们不得不四项诉讼合并
so we had to bundle like four actions together,
当时我以为我们完了
and I was sure that we were sunk.
但是您  您引用了什么来着
But you -- you quoted... what was it?
艾迪斯敦钢管厂
Huh? Addyston Pipe & Steel.
您把官司导向了反垄断
You turned it all antitrust,
然后这官司赢得了简易判决
and the whole thing went away in summary judgment.
太棒了  太棒了
It was amazing. It was amazing.
我还想有一天您一定会在最高法院辩护呢
I figured you'd be arguing in front of the supreme court someday.
好吧  很高兴见到你
Well, it's, uh, good to see you.
好的
Yeah.
好吧  我们谈正事儿吧
All right, well, let's get started.
我们读过了你修改过后的律师函
Um, we've read your revised demand.
真是一长串啊  很有创意
It's, uh, quite a laundry list. Very creative.
是啊  很有创意  你们的客户
Yeah, creative, like the way
搜刮那些老人的方式也很有创意
your clients have been billing my clients.
像达利[著名画家]般的超现实创意
'Cause that's like Salvador Dalí Creative.
说得好  但是你说的是站不住脚的
That's cute. Y-you know, you're not gonna make this stick.
先不说垃圾堆里的"证据"
Setting aside evidentiary concerns --
你们连十块钱一把的锁都买不起吗
Whoa, whoa. Your guys couldn't afford 10 bucks for a padlock?
这是他们的问题  那是公共财产
That's on them. Public property.
或许有的法官会像你这么想
Maybe a judge sees that your way, maybe he doesn't.
但是想要以虐待老人索赔
But the damages for elder abuse?
法律要求必须存在不当胁迫
The statute requires proof that there was some undue influence --
矶鹞渡的老人必须受到威胁才行
Someone threatening the residents of Sandpiper Crossing.
据我所知
As far as I understand it,
没有老人声称有人拿刀威胁他们
no one has claimed there's a guy with a knife
叫他们把午餐钱交出来
telling them to hand over their lunch money.
外面是有很多名声很差的
There are a lot of assisted-living facilities
生活协助中心
out there that may be disreputable,
但我们的客户不是  一点都不是
but that's not the case with our client, not even close.
他们所有的中心  全部十二个
All their facilities -- all 12 of them --
每一所都是五星级的
every single one, five-star rated.
你现在随便去一家
You go to any one of them right now,
知道你会看到什么吗
and you know what you'll see?
你会看到幸福健康的老人们
You'll see happy, healthy residents.
矶鹞渡把他们照顾得很好
Sandpiper takes care of these people.
没有蒙骗他们
They don't bilk them.
然而我们还是做了调查
But we looked into it,
你的有些客户确实被多收了钱
and some of your clients have, in fact, been overbilled.
这只是审计出了错
It's -- it's an accounting error.
并没有到诈骗的程度  完全没有
It doesn't rise to the level of fraud, not even close.
我们算了下损失  共计46320元
We've calculated the damages. All told, it's $46,320.
我们准备这样做
Mm-hmm, so here's what we're prepared to do.
我们会还你的客户一个公道
We're gonna make your clients whole --
一张支票用于支付那四万六千多
A check for the $46,000 and change right now.
另外
And on top of that,
我们还会支付你四万六千美元作为补偿
We'll give you another $46k to cover your expenses.
一共是多少  九万两千美元
So what's that? $92,000?
凑个整  十万美元
Let's call it $100,000 even.
我们没有犯罪
We admit to no wrongdoing,
你的委托人也撤销所有控告
and your clients release all claims.
我认为你们得再好好考虑一下
I think you're gonna need to do better than that.
你在你的律师函里提到过
Ah, this was in your demand letter.
是注射器  有什么问题吗
They're syringes. So?
不知道你是否了解
I-I don't know if you know this,
这是生活协助中心一项标准收费项目
but that's a pretty standard item in an assisted-living facility.
没错  不过问题不在器材本身
Correct. But it's not what it is that matters.
而在于这些器材的来源
It's where it's from.
内布拉斯加州  林肯市
Lincoln, Nebraska.
内布拉斯加州居民的绰号
上啊  内布拉斯剥皮机
Go, Cornhuskers.
既然你没搞明白我的意思
Well, since you're not picking up what I'm putting down,
那就让我来解释一下
I'll explain it to you.
内布拉斯加  虽然都是"N"打头的
Um, Nebraska, although they both begin with the letter "N,"
但实际上它和新墨西哥州却是两码事
actually turns out to be a different state than New Mexico.
所以说你的客户为了做生意
So your client accepted shipments
接受跨州界运货
across state lines for its enterprise.
竟然还是通过美国邮政
I-in the U.S. Mail, no less.
RICO  反诈骗腐败组织集团犯罪法
你是想把它当成诈骗案处理吗
Are you trying to make this a RICO case?
美国犯罪团伙头目
你以为我们的客户是约翰·高蒂吗
Like our client is John Gotti or something?
你我都清楚
Well, you know as well as I do
RICO主要适用于商业案件
RICO's used mostly for business beefs.
塞迪玛一案降低了
Sedima establishes a pretty low threshold
RICO的适用门槛
for RICO provisions to kick in.
你们这是违法跨州界贸易哦
Interstate commerce is a bitch, huh?
我们一旦确定了...
As soon as we establish a pattern to --
你们管它叫什么来着  "额外收费"
What was your word? Uh, "Overbillings"?
我更喜欢用传统术语"诈骗"
I prefer the classic term of "Fraud."
你们将面临三倍损害赔偿
You're looking at treble damages.
你出的十万块算什么
So your 100 grand --
这下应该站得住脚了吧
I think you know where you can stick it.
能给我们几分钟吗
Will you give us a moment?
这样吧
Well...
你们给个确切的数
What number exactly did you have in mind?
两千万美元
$20 million.
-你说什么  -你已经听到了
- Excuse me? - You heard me.
-你别指望着...  -两千万  美元
- Oh, you can't expect - $20 million.
要不就法庭见
Or we'll see you in court.
两千万
$20 million?
你没听他们说吗
Didn't you hear them?
这可是个大公司  十二个分中心
This is a big company. 12 separate facilities.
不可能全在新墨西哥州
They can't possibly all be in New Mexico.
这很可能是一个跨州的
This is potentially a multi-state
联邦集体诉讼案件
federal class-action lawsuit
在定罪阶段还有RICO助力
with a RICO kicker at the penalty phase.
两千万还是客气的
$20 million? That's conservative.
现在我们要从集体诉讼确认入手
Now, class cert -- that's where we start.
我来起草诉状  尽量搞定有条件的
I'll draft our complaint, try to get us a conditional one.
他们会想办法突破
They'll try to pierce it,
但是应该能拖到他们被强制要求吐露实情
but it should hold long enough to start discovery.
我们得先解决你的问题
And we need to get you back on the grounds,
撤销你的禁令
quash this prohibition against you.
通过禁令救济  或者搞个监时禁止令
Uh, some injunctive relief. Maybe a T.R.O.
吉米
Jimmy?
还不开始弄监时禁止令
Do you want to get started on the T.R.O.?
好  马上
Yeah. Yes.
状态很不错  没长心丝虫  也没长癣
It looks good. No heartworm, no mange.
-你从哪儿找到它的  -收容所
- Where did you get her? - Shelter.
挺好  幼犬繁殖场有很多
Good. There's too many puppy mills out there.
一种短腿长身的德国种猎犬
前几天来了一只达克斯
I had a dachsie in the other day.
被喂得太饱  可怜的小东西
Some douche bred her so much, poor thing,
肚子上长了个巨大的疝气瘤
she just had one giant hernia for a belly.
连路都走不了
Couldn't even walk.
要我说那些人就该下地狱
Those people can go straight to hell, as far as I'm concerned.
还有什么需要帮忙的吗
Anything else I can do for you?
你和那些人还有联系吗
You still in touch with your people?
那得看你想找什么样的工作
Depends on the type of work you're looking for --
你能做的  不能做的  想做的  不想做的
Your dos, your don'ts, your wills, your won'ts.
告诉我你能提供什么工作
Well, if you tell me what you've got,
我就告诉你我能做什么
I'll tell you what I'll do.
今天我在购物中心又签了三个客户
I signed up three more clients at the mall today.
天哪  那些逛商场的
Jesus, those mall walkers...
老头老太太走路还挺快的
Those geezers are faster than you think.
累得我可以睡上十年
I could sleep for a decade.
你拿到我要的东西了吗
Did you get what I asked?
那些法典条文
The, uh, code provisions? Ohh.
靠
Shit.
放车里了
Uh, it's in the car.
先让我躺一分钟  我就...
Just give me a minute. I'll, uh...
我就去取
I'll go.
那个...
Where's the...
查克
Chuck?
怎么了
Yeah.